rockwellcollins.com 2017-10-02

# Privacy & Cookies

Privacy Statement   
Cookie Statement

Privacy Statement 

**Last updated September 2017**

**Introduction**

Rockwell Collins Inc. is committed to protecting your privacy. This statement details the steps we take to protect your personal information when you visit our website, mobile applications or various other sites hosted by our service providers on our behalf (collectively the “Sites”). It describes the personal information that we collect, the purposes for which we use such information, and your choices regarding our use of it. The steps we take to protect your personal information and how you can review and correct your personal information are also covered here. By accessing our Sites, you are consenting to the information collection and use practices described in this policy.

**Our collection of information**

_Information collected directly from you._

Generally, you can visit Rockwell Collins Sites without entering any personal information. On certain pages, we may ask you for personal information to provide a service or carry out a transaction that you have requested. The personal information we collect may include:

  * Contact details, such as your name, title, company/organization name, email address, telephone and fax numbers, and physical address; 
  * Information about your company and job function; 
  * Your email marketing preference; 
  * Financial information (including credit card or account information); 
  * Information such as your nationality and country of residence that allows us to determine your eligibility under export control regulations to receive information about certain technologies; 
  * Information used to customize and facilitate your use of our Sites, including login and technical information; 
  * Inquiries about and orders for our products and services; 
  * Information that assists us in identifying the products and services that best meet your requirements; 
  * Event registration information; and 
  * Feedback from you about our Sites and our products and services generally.

If you make an application for a position with Rockwell Collins, or if you are a current employee of Rockwell Collins, we may collect the following information from you through our online portal:

  * Resume or CV, cover letter, previous work experience, educational background, type of employment sought, date available, employee referral, desired salary, travel preferences, information about your performance and career developments;
  * Identification, such as your passport number, expatriate status, government identification numbers (e.g. Social Security Number) where permitted, immigration status, nationality, and, where permitted, information concerning your heritage and ethnicity (for diversity monitoring purposes);
  * Bank account and payment details, compensation, and information about your health and sickness leave, work expenses, employee benefits and use of company resources, and your signature;
  * Photographs and personal details you provide in a profile; and
  * Any other information you submit to us, including any correspondences you may have with us.

You are not required to provide any of this information, but if you do not, we may not be able to provide you the requested service or complete your transaction.

_Information collected automatically._

We collect information about your visit to our Sites, including what pages you view, the date and time you access the site, the number of bytes transferred, links you click, the materials you access, and other actions taken within Rockwell Collins' Sites. On Sites that you enter with a user ID, we may connect this information with your identity to determine your potential interests in our products and services. We also collect certain standard information that your browser sends to every Site you visit, such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address, your browser type and capabilities and language, your operating system, and the website from which you linked to our Site. 

_Information from other sources_

We may obtain information about you from other sources, such as where your employer supplies your contact details though our customer portal. If you make an application for employment with us or accept employment with us, we may obtain information from third parties, including, to the extent permitted by applicable law, recruiters, employment research firms, identity verification services, the references you provide to us, websites and other publicly accessible information on the Internet. We may also receive information you submit to us through third-party websites, including through LinkedIn, and other publicly available sources. Where permitted by local law and with your consent, we may request background or credit checks from public authorities or financial institutions to evaluate your eligibility for employment or certain Rockwell Collins positions or projects, as well as your medical information if required to evaluate your eligibility for employment benefits.

**Use of information**

_Services and transactions._ We use your personal information to deliver services or carry out transactions you have requested, such as providing information on Rockwell Collins products, registering purchased products, processing product orders, handling warranty claims, providing product manuals, answering customer service requests, receiving Rockwell Collins purchase orders and managing supplier information, facilitating use of our Sites, and so forth. In order to offer you a more consistent experience in your interactions with Rockwell Collins, information collected by our Sites may be combined with information we collect by other means.

_Website improvement._ We may use your personal information to improve our Sites and related Rockwell Collins products and services, or to make our Sites easier to use by eliminating the need for you to repeatedly enter the same information or by customizing our Sites to your particular preferences or interests.

_Employment applications._ We ask you for personal information in connection with a job application or inquiry, such as information about yourself, a resume or curriculum vitae. We may use this information throughout Rockwell Collins and its controlled subsidiaries and affiliates for the purpose of employment consideration. We will keep the information for future consideration unless you direct us not to do so. If you accept a position with Rockwell Collins, we will retain this information as part of the employment relationship. 

_Employee portal._   If you are a Rockwell Collins employee or contractor, we may offer portals or other pages on the Site to serve as a central resource for human resources functions and other functions related to the employment relationship. We may use your personal information to manage your rights, benefits, insurance plans, pensions, absences, compensation, training, leadership development, travel and other employment functions. We may also use your personal information, where permitted, for diversity monitoring, ethics and other compliance requirements. You may have the option to create an employee profile which is included in company directories and allows you to communicate and share information with other Rockwell Collins employees and contractors.

**Sharing of information**

_Disclosure of your personal information._ Except as described below, personal information you provide to Rockwell Collins through our Sites will not be shared outside of Rockwell Collins and its controlled subsidiaries and affiliates without your permission.

_Disclosure to service providers._ Rockwell Collins contracts with other companies to provide services on our behalf, such as hosting Sites, sending out information, processing transactions, and analyzing our Sites. We provide these companies with only those elements of your personal information they need to deliver those services. These companies and their employees are prohibited from using that personal information for any other purpose.

_Disclosure to distributors._ In responding to a request made by you, we may share your personal information with companies that distribute our products or services. In those cases, we provide these companies with only those elements of your personal information they need to respond to your request, and these companies and their employees are prohibited from using that personal information for any other purpose. In some cases, we may seek your permission to share your information with distributors for marketing purposes other than responding to a request from you. However, we will not share your information for such marketing purposes unless we have obtained your express consent to do so.

_Disclosure on employee and applicant portals._ If you apply for a position with Rockwell Collins through our online portal, or use the portal as an employee or contractor, some personal information will be made available to Rockwell Collins, Inc. to administer the Sites and manage group functions, as well as with any other group company with whom you make an application, for whom you are employed, or with whom you communicate.

_Disclosure in connection with transactions._ In connection with certain transactions, we may disclose some or all of your personal information to financial institutions, government entities, and shipping companies or postal services involved in fulfillment.

_Disclosure in connection with acquisitions or divestitures._ Circumstances may arise where for strategic or other business reasons Rockwell Collins decides to sell, buy or otherwise reorganize businesses in some countries. Such a transaction may involve disclosure of personal information to prospective or actual purchasers, or receiving it from sellers. It is Rockwell Collins' practice to seek appropriate protection for information in these types of transactions.

_Disclosure for other reasons._ We may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with legal requirements or with legal process served on us, to protect and defend our rights or property, or in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of any individual.

**Security**

Rockwell Collins is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer systems with limited access that are located in facilities to which access is limited. For Sites to which you log in, it is your responsibility to ensure the security of your password and not to reveal this information to others. When you move around a site to which you have logged in, or from one site to another that uses the same login mechanism, we verify your identity by means of an encrypted cookie placed on your machine.

**Your choices and rights**

In some cases, you can review and correct personal information you provide through our Sites by going to the page on which you provided the information. In all cases, you can make a request to review and correct your personal information collected via our public-facing Sites or ask Rockwell Collins to stop using it by contacting us at [www.rockwellcollins.com/Contact_Us.aspx](https://www.rockwellcollins.com/Contact_Us.aspx) or by visiting our Site at [www.rockwellcollins.com](https://www.rockwellcollins.com/), clicking on  "Contact Us," selecting the “General” option, and completing the online form. We may take steps to verify your identity before providing you access to your personal information. You can help us to maintain the accuracy of your information by notifying us of any change to your mailing address, phone number, or email address.

If you provided personal information to us as part of an application for a position with Rockwell Collins or as part of your employment relationship with us and you have any questions about our information handling practices, please contact our Employee Service Center at [ employeeservice@rockwellcollins.com](mailto:employeeservice@rockwellcollins.com) or your local Human Resources Manager.

_For residents of the European Union_

If you reside in the European Union, you may have the right to ask Rockwell Collins for a copy of your personal information; or to correct, delete or restrict processing of your personal information; or to receive a copy of your personal information in a structured, machine readable format. o:p>

In addition, you can object to the processing of your personal information in some circumstances and, where we have asked for your consent, you may withdraw it at any time. These rights may be limited, for example if fulfilling your request would reveal personal information about another person, if we have compelling legitimate interests, or if you ask us to delete information which we are required by law to keep. 

We will retain your personal information only for as long as we need it for a legitimate interest, to fulfil your employment contract or perform a service at your request, or to meet a legal requirement, after which we will take steps to delete your personal information or hold it in a form that no longer identifies you. 

You may request to fulfill any of these rights by completing our online form (see above instructions for access to the “Contact Us” link). If your request relates to information you provided as part of an application to or employment with Rockwell Collins, please contact our Employee Service Center at [ employeeservice@rockwellcollins.com](mailto:employeeservice@rockwellcollins.com) o or your local Human Resources Manager. If you have unresolved concerns, you have the right to complain to a data protection authority. The data controllers for your personal data are the Rockwell Collins office to which you have made an application, the Rockwell Collins office that employs you, as well as Rockwell Collins, Inc.

**International transfers of personal information**

Personal information collected on our Websites may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Rockwell Collins or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities. If you are using our Sites to make an application to Rockwell Collins or as part of your employment relationship with us, your information may be shared for legitimate business needs to our offices in other countries that may not have the same data protection standards as those in your country of residence. If you reside in a country that regulates such transfers, we take steps to adequately address the relevant requirements. For further information, you may contact us as described in the “Your choices and rights” section above. 

**Links to other sites**

Our Sites may contain links to other sites such as professional and government organizations. We also link to third-party providers that host, maintain and operate on-line training or services. While we try to link only to sites that share our high standards and respect for privacy, we are not responsible for the content, security, or privacy practices employed by other sites.

**Enforcement of this privacy statement**

If you have questions regarding this statement or our handling of your personal information, please contact us. We will promptly address your concern and strive to reach a satisfactory resolution.

**Changes to this privacy statement**

Rockwell Collins may occasionally update this privacy statement. If we do, we will revise the "last updated" date at the top and bottom of the privacy statement. 

**Last Updated September 2017**

Cookie Statement

**Last updated September 2017**

**What is a cookie?**

A cookie is either a small text file that is stored on your hard drive, or some information that is stored in memory until you close your browser. Any given website can store and read only its own cookies; it cannot read a cookie set by another website, nor can it inject information into cookies set by other websites.

**What is its purpose?**

A cookie helps website operators monitor usage of their website, and it also enables them to provide a secure personalized browsing experience for their users. In addition, cookies are often used on eCommerce websites to facilitate the shopping experience.

Rockwell Collins uses or may use cookies in the following ways:

  * To store session information while users are browsing its websites.
  * To enable more accurate reporting of site usage data, such as new visitors, unique visitors and returning visitors.
  * To enable targeted content to be served on its sites or other third party sites based on your browsing history (see privacy considerations below).

**What kind of cookies do we use?**

Strictly necessary cookies: we use strictly necessary cookies to facilitate the correct navigation of the website and portal as well as to ensure that content loads effectively. These cookies are essential to providing the services or any features you have requested.

Performance cookies: we use cookies that track aggregate statistics related to our page views and the navigation of visitors to our online services. The information we collect enables us to improve the quality of your online experience, through assisting us in building user-friendly and trouble-shooting issues.

Functionality cookies: we use functionality cookies to remember choices you make (such as language preference, country location, or other online settings) and provide the personalized or enhanced features that you select. Our functionality cookies can be used to provide online services to you, or to prevent online services from being offered to you if you previously indicated you did not want to receive such services. We do not use functionality cookies to identify you; however, we may use these cookies to track your browsing across our websites and online portal.

Third-party cookies: We may use third party cookies for marketing and analytics purposes. These are cookies that are managed by a domain name different from Rockwell Collins, including:

  * Google Inc.: for the purpose of providing its Google Analytics service, which allows Rockwell Collins to understand how users interact with the website. 
  * Siteimprove: for the purpose of collecting data that helps Rockwell Collins understand how users interact within the website.
  * MultiView, Inc.: for the purpose of providing targeted advertising on behalf of Rockwell Collins as you browse other websites.
  * LinkedIn: for the purpose of helping Rockwell Collins understand the effectiveness of its posts and advertising on the LinkedIn website.

**Cookies and your privacy**

A cookie cannot read data from elsewhere on your computer; thus, it cannot steal any personally identifiable information about you. A cookie could store your personal information only if you had first entered it into a Web form and then the operators of the website chose to store it as part of the cookie. Rockwell Collins may request and store personal information to customize your experience on our sites. We will never share this information with third parties without your consent, except where required by law.

As stated earlier, a given website cannot read cookies set by other websites. However, websites can include content, such as banner images, from third-party sites that set their own cookies. Subsequently, other sites that you visit that include content from the same third-party site may be customized based on your previous browsing history. In this manner, it may appear as though these sites have read your cookies, but it is really because of the third-party cookie.

**_Example:_** You visit an automaker's website, and that site includes content from a third-party site that sets its own cookie. Subsequently, you visit other websites that incorporate content from the same third party. The third-party website knows that you looked at cars on the automaker's website and thus may show ads featuring that automaker’s vehicles.

**Controlling cookies**

Rockwell Collins recognizes its users' privacy concerns. You may choose to reject cookies either outright, or on a case-by-case basis. However, please be aware that our applications and websites may require you to accept cookies in order to use some or all of their features.

If you wish to withdraw your consent to this Cookies Policy at any time, you should delete the cookies stored on your device via the settings and configurations on your internet browser.

You can allow, block or delete installed cookies on your computer by configuring the options of the web browser installed on your computer. For more information, refer to the following links.

**Contact**

If you have any questions or comments regarding this Cookie Policy, you may contact us at [www.rockwellcollins.com/Contact_Us.aspx](https://www.rockwellcollins.com/Contact_Us.aspx) or by visiting our Site at [www.rockwellcollins.com](https://www.rockwellcollins.com/), clicking on "Contact Us," selecting the “General” option, and completing the online form.

If you choose to contact us, any personal data included your communication with us will be processed in accordance with our privacy policy set forth in the above Privacy Statement.

**Last updated September 2017**
